DEVESH SRIVASTAVA

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

+91 99993055585

@ devesh.kr.sri@gmail.com

~ Gurgaon, India

+ linkedin.com/in/devesh-srivastava-94268516



SUMMARY

Full stack developer with overall 13 years of experience in designing and development front end, back end application using React JS, Redux, Angular, Node.js, Jest with Enzyme, GraphQL, RESTfull API, Docker, MongoDB, .Net and CI/CD with Azure cloud. Performed technical lead role in UK for 6 years.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Accenture

~ 03/2018 - Present

+ Accenture UK

Digital Squad Project: Working with mortgages team to facilitate its digital transformation using the latest tech stack using React.

- Responsible for designing & developing front end components for digital mortgage application using React JS, Redux, Express, MongoDB, GraphQL, RESTfull API, Material UI, and Node.js.
- Setup and configured CI/CD pipeline with Docker to deploy applications to the Azure using Azure Dev-Ops.
- Highly focused Unit and End-To-End test, using a TDD approach with tools like Jest & Enzyme.

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Accenture

~ 03/2015 - 03/2018

+ Accenture UK

MDC Project: Designed and developed web-based components for a variety of applications in an agile development setting in MDC.

- Create custom components in React JS, Redux (internal UI library) that can be used companywide so that we have common UI across applications.
- Design and implementation of the 99.99% up-time REST API for the business-critical online service using node.js, express.
- Performed planning, estimation, coding, bug fixing & code reviews

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Accenture

~ 09/2011 - 03/2015

+ Accenture UK/India

CBIA Project: Designed and developed web-based components for a variety of applications in an agile development setting.

- Architected and designed enterprise applications for project using Angular, AWS Lambda, & SQL server.
- Build technical architecture for reporting applications.
- Developed MVC, .net, C# project to build front end application.
- Consulted in a redesign of the company's website, resulting in a 25% increase in traffic.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Accenture

~ 09/2009 - 09/2011

- + Accenture India
- Lead Development team for banking applications using C#, ASP.NET MVC, JavaScript, and CSS.
- Implement the module based on the change request, along with the build, code review, unit testing & deployment of the application.
- Ensure proper documentation and reports in all stages of the application development life cycle.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATION

IGNOU

~ 2005

BA ECONOMICS HONORS

CHENNAI UNIVERSITY

~ 2003

ORGANIZATIONS

ACCENTURE PRIVATE LIMITED (08/2009 - Present)

Team Lead

PATNI COMPUTER SYSTEM (01/2008 - 08/2009)

Senior Software Developer

FCF Software Solution LTD (06/2006 - 07/2007)

Software Developer

SKILLS

ReactJS Redux **Angular** ES₆ Webpack Babel **Material UI** CSS3 **BOOTSTRAP** HTML5 **JAVASCRIPT TYPESCRIPT NODE.JS** RESTFULL API **EXPRESS** GraphQL **GIT GITHUB JIRA TFS** TESTING: Jest, Enzyme, Karma DB: MySQL, MongoDB PostgresSQL, SQL Server **DEPLOYMENT: Kubernetes, Docker** Heroku, AWS, Azure Agile, Kanban .net, C#, MVC

ACHIEVEMENTS

- PRIDE AWARD AT ACCENTURE FOR OUTSTANDING CONTRIBUTION TO THE PROJECT IN 2016.
- SCRUM MASTER CERTIFIED, CERTIFIED IN MICROSOFT AZURE DEVELOPER AND ADMINISTRATOR.